<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intellectual Property Court on Chen Tianhao</title>
    <link>https://sypthu.github.io/tags/intellectual-property-court/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intellectual Property Court on Chen Tianhao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:39:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sypthu.github.io/tags/intellectual-property-court/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Intellectual Property Courts in China: Governance Effectiveness and Institutional Logic</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-intellectual-property-courts-in-chinagovernance-effectiveness-and-institutional-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-intellectual-property-courts-in-chinagovernance-effectiveness-and-institutional-logic/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Yipo Su
Abstract An analysis of innovation and R&amp;amp;D data of listed companies from 2011 to 2020 using difference-in-difference estimation method shows that the intellectual property courts established in China at the end of 2014 have achieved positive governance effectiveness. Intellectual property courts can play a prominent role in promoting corporate innovation by improving the efficiency of dispute resolution and enhancing normative output through adjudication. A retrospective look at the creation, establishment and development of intellectual property courts reveals that the legitimacy pressures they face as newly created organizations and their behavioral logic of upward response and horizontal competition have together driven their efforts to improve the efficiency and quality of adjudication in the past practice, thereby providing a concrete example of improving the effectiveness of judicial governance and accumulating valuable experience for the subsequent construction of specialized courts and the promotion of judicial reform.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
