<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chen Tianhao</title>
    <link>https://sypthu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Chen Tianhao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sypthu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Judicializing Public Interests: Administrative Performance Under the Shadow of Judicial Review</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/judicializing-public-interestsadministrative-performance-under-the-shadow-of-judicial-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/judicializing-public-interestsadministrative-performance-under-the-shadow-of-judicial-review/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Yu Sheng, Wei Xu and Xiaohong Yu*
Abstract Do active judicial reviews bring about better administrative performance? Most scholars argue that active judicial review creates animosity between the judiciary and administration, leading to bad administrative performance. Others advocate a less hostile but constructive relationship between the two. However, the actual impact and mechanism of such a constructive relationship remain unclear. Employing an analysis of Public Interest Litigation against the Administration (PILA) in China, we present a theory of “bargaining in the shadow of judicial review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legal Environment of Intellectual Property and Innovation: The Moderating Role of Legal Mobilization</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/legal-environment-of-intellectual-property-and-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/legal-environment-of-intellectual-property-and-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Yipo Su, Yuhan Liu, Yuan Zhou*
Abstract Scholars have mainly studied how court decisions in intellectual property (IP) litigation impact firms&amp;rsquo; innovation while overlooking the equally important role of courts&amp;rsquo; reasoning in shaping the IP legal environment that influences innovation. To address this gap, we analyzed 99,565 judicial decision documents from three Chinese IP courts spanning 2015 to 2020. Using both dictionary-based and machine learning-based methods, we precisely measured each firm&amp;rsquo;s IP legal environment shaped by judge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Litigation in China: Assessing the Chief Officials Appearance System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-litigation-in-chinaassessing-the-chief-officials-appearance-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-litigation-in-chinaassessing-the-chief-officials-appearance-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Wei Xu and Xiaohong Yu*
Abstract The Chief Officials Appearance System (COAS), introduced in 2015, requires government leaders to appear in court and explain their actions. Unlike other post-2014 legal reforms aiming to reduce political influence in administrative litigation, COAS uniquely actively involves political officials. This approach is based on the belief that increased participation will help officials better understand public concerns and improve administrative litigation quality. However, few studies have examined the system’s effectiveness, and existing research relies on anecdotal evidence with limited analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Intellectual Property Courts in China: Governance Effectiveness and Institutional Logic</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-intellectual-property-courts-in-chinagovernance-effectiveness-and-institutional-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-intellectual-property-courts-in-chinagovernance-effectiveness-and-institutional-logic/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Yipo Su
Abstract An analysis of innovation and R&amp;amp;D data of listed companies from 2011 to 2020 using difference-in-difference estimation method shows that the intellectual property courts established in China at the end of 2014 have achieved positive governance effectiveness. Intellectual property courts can play a prominent role in promoting corporate innovation by improving the efficiency of dispute resolution and enhancing normative output through adjudication. A retrospective look at the creation, establishment and development of intellectual property courts reveals that the legitimacy pressures they face as newly created organizations and their behavioral logic of upward response and horizontal competition have together driven their efforts to improve the efficiency and quality of adjudication in the past practice, thereby providing a concrete example of improving the effectiveness of judicial governance and accumulating valuable experience for the subsequent construction of specialized courts and the promotion of judicial reform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreement Integration and Improvement of Modification and Termination System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-integration-and-improvement-of-modification-and-termination-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-integration-and-improvement-of-modification-and-termination-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract How should the situation change and statutory termination system of civil contracts be referenced and applied to administrative agreements? Taking into account existing regulations and the judicial practices of people&amp;rsquo;s courts, it can be seen that when there is a fundamental breach of the agreement&amp;rsquo;s counterparty or it encounters force majeure and situation change, the contracting administrative entity should, in principle, refer to and apply the situation change and statutory termination system of civil contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codification of French Administrative Law: Origins, Exploration, and Borrowing</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/codification-of-french-administrative-laworigins-exploration-and-borrowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/codification-of-french-administrative-laworigins-exploration-and-borrowing/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The choice of the development path for codifying French administrative law can be traced back to a reevaluation of its traditional common law development path. In the early stages of administrative law development, the common law development path was capable of overcoming the normative dispersion of statutory law, filling gaps in statutory norms, and avoiding direct conflicts with administrative authorities. However, in the latter half of the 20th century, common law became increasingly incapable of meeting the demands for democracy and systematization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Administrative Agreement Legality Review Mechanism Establishment</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreement-legality-review-mechanism-establishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreement-legality-review-mechanism-establishment/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The People&amp;rsquo;s Court, when adjudicating disputes over the performance of administrative agreements, needs to consider the administrative agreement&amp;rsquo;s legality and validity as a prerequisite. However, the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Provisions on Several Issues Concerning the Adjudication of Administrative Agreement Cases&amp;rdquo; has not established a specific mechanism for reviewing the legality and validity of administrative agreements. Based on the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s judicial practices regarding administrative agreements since 2015, this article, with the support of the existing regulatory framework, extracts three aspects of the legality and validity review criteria: subject authority, procedure/form, and agreement content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Procuratorial Administrative Public Interest Litigation System: Effectiveness Test and Improvement Path——An Empirical Analysis Using the Difference-in-Difference Method</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-procuratorial-administrative-public-interest-litigation-systemeffectiveness-test-and-improvement-pathan-empirical-analysis-using-the-difference-in-difference-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-procuratorial-administrative-public-interest-litigation-systemeffectiveness-test-and-improvement-pathan-empirical-analysis-using-the-difference-in-difference-method/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Jianshu Shao and Xuechun Wang
Abstract The key strategy to the continued effectiveness of administrative public interest litigation systems should be to activate the local horizontal supervision mechanism rather than to eliminate the &amp;ldquo;state-centeredness&amp;rdquo; of the system. Using a difference-in-differences (DID) estimation method, this paper reveals the administrative public interest litigation system, which is in the path of &amp;ldquo;state-centricity&amp;rdquo;, has a significant negative impact on discharge of industrial wastewater during the pilot period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreement Litigation: The Construction and Improvement of the System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The new &amp;ldquo;Administrative Litigation Law&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Judicial Interpretation on Administrative Agreements&amp;rdquo; have expanded the jurisdiction of administrative litigation to encompass disputes over the effectiveness of administrative agreements, performance disputes, and disputes involving high authorities. They have also &amp;ldquo;relationship-orientedly&amp;rdquo; transformed the administrative agreement litigation system. When the People&amp;rsquo;s Court handles these disputes, it should move beyond the traditional logic of reviewing the legitimacy of administrative actions and allocate the rights and interests of all parties appropriately based on the overall legal relationship of administrative agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Administrative Agreements: The Principle of Equality in a Comparative Legal Perspective on the Intersection of Civil Law and Administrative Law</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreementsthe-principle-of-equality-in-a-comparative-legal-perspective-on-the-intersection-of-civil-law-and-administrative-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreementsthe-principle-of-equality-in-a-comparative-legal-perspective-on-the-intersection-of-civil-law-and-administrative-law/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract An administrative agreement represents an initiative by the administrative authority to enter the market and seek cooperation with market entities. The parties involved can only reach an agreement on rights and obligations through equal negotiations, thereby establishing an administrative agreement relationship, which is fully consistent with civil contracts. The modern evolution of the foundations of public law and administrative law has also transformed the relationship between administrative authorities and counterparties from the traditional &amp;ldquo;command-obedience&amp;rdquo; model to a gradually emerging state of equality with dual legal status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreements: The Identification and Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract Since the enactment of the new Administrative Litigation Law in 2015, judges in the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s administrative division have tended to expand the boundaries of administrative agreements by emphasizing the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative duties,&amp;rdquo; while judges in the civil division of the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court have tended to restrict the boundaries based on the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative powers.&amp;rdquo; The source of this divergence lies in the inherent tension between the values of &amp;ldquo;safeguarding the public interest&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;respecting private rights&amp;rdquo; in China&amp;rsquo;s Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/index-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/index-about/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A law and public administration scholar with a curious mind, and 5+ years of teaching and research experience. Research interests encompass administrative law, administrative agreements, judicial governance, and technology ethics.
Professional history School of Public Policy &amp;amp; Management, Tsinghua University, Associate Professor
June 2021– Present
School of Public Policy &amp;amp; Management, Tsinghua University, Assistant Professor
December 2017 – May2021
Social career The Fourth &amp;ldquo;Legal Research Scholars of the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Salon and Media Interviews</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/media/</guid>
      <description>Interviewed by Caixin over the ethics in science and technology, October, 2023 Tianhao Chen states that Measures for Scientific and Technological Ethics Review (for Trial Implementation) has set up the organization and procedure for the review of scientific and technological ethics. He holds the view that the incentive logic of the institutions and the operational logic of the scientific and technological ethics (review) committees are contradictory, “one is the accelerator, and the other is the brake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydra</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/legislation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/legislation/</guid>
      <description>Motto Cut off one head and two will take their place</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Conferences with My Team</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/conference/</guid>
      <description>17th Annual Conference of the European China Law Studies Association, September, 2023 Position：Helsinki, Netherlands Panel：New Public Interest Law Title：Judicializing Public Interests: Administrative Performance Under the Shadow of Judicial Review Author：Tianhao Chen, Yu Sheng, Wei Xu and Xiaohong Yu (Tsinghua University) 19th International Symposium on Global Manufacturing and China, September, 2023 Hangzhou, China Panel：IP Rights and Innovation Capability Title：Perceived Legal Environment of Intellectual Property and Firm Innovation: The Moderating Role of Legal mobilization Author：Tianhao Chen, Yipo Su, Yuhan Liu, Yuan Zhou Result：Best Paper Awards 83rd Academy of Management Meeting , August, 2023 Position：Boston, USA Panel：Innovation and Intellectual Property Title：Legal Environment of Intellectual Property and Innovation: The Moderating Role of Legal Mobilization Author：Tianhao Chen, Yipo Su, Yuhan Liu, Yuan Zhou </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tatooine</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/tatooine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/activities/tatooine/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away&amp;hellip;. A project was planned, but never completed</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
