<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administrative Agreement on Chen Tianhao</title>
    <link>https://sypthu.github.io/tags/administrative-agreement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Administrative Agreement on Chen Tianhao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 23:39:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sypthu.github.io/tags/administrative-agreement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreement Integration and Improvement of Modification and Termination System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-integration-and-improvement-of-modification-and-termination-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-integration-and-improvement-of-modification-and-termination-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract How should the situation change and statutory termination system of civil contracts be referenced and applied to administrative agreements? Taking into account existing regulations and the judicial practices of people&amp;rsquo;s courts, it can be seen that when there is a fundamental breach of the agreement&amp;rsquo;s counterparty or it encounters force majeure and situation change, the contracting administrative entity should, in principle, refer to and apply the situation change and statutory termination system of civil contracts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Administrative Agreement Legality Review Mechanism Establishment</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreement-legality-review-mechanism-establishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreement-legality-review-mechanism-establishment/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The People&amp;rsquo;s Court, when adjudicating disputes over the performance of administrative agreements, needs to consider the administrative agreement&amp;rsquo;s legality and validity as a prerequisite. However, the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Provisions on Several Issues Concerning the Adjudication of Administrative Agreement Cases&amp;rdquo; has not established a specific mechanism for reviewing the legality and validity of administrative agreements. Based on the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s judicial practices regarding administrative agreements since 2015, this article, with the support of the existing regulatory framework, extracts three aspects of the legality and validity review criteria: subject authority, procedure/form, and agreement content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreement Litigation: The Construction and Improvement of the System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The new &amp;ldquo;Administrative Litigation Law&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Judicial Interpretation on Administrative Agreements&amp;rdquo; have expanded the jurisdiction of administrative litigation to encompass disputes over the effectiveness of administrative agreements, performance disputes, and disputes involving high authorities. They have also &amp;ldquo;relationship-orientedly&amp;rdquo; transformed the administrative agreement litigation system. When the People&amp;rsquo;s Court handles these disputes, it should move beyond the traditional logic of reviewing the legitimacy of administrative actions and allocate the rights and interests of all parties appropriately based on the overall legal relationship of administrative agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Administrative Agreements: The Principle of Equality in a Comparative Legal Perspective on the Intersection of Civil Law and Administrative Law</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreementsthe-principle-of-equality-in-a-comparative-legal-perspective-on-the-intersection-of-civil-law-and-administrative-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/the-administrative-agreementsthe-principle-of-equality-in-a-comparative-legal-perspective-on-the-intersection-of-civil-law-and-administrative-law/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract An administrative agreement represents an initiative by the administrative authority to enter the market and seek cooperation with market entities. The parties involved can only reach an agreement on rights and obligations through equal negotiations, thereby establishing an administrative agreement relationship, which is fully consistent with civil contracts. The modern evolution of the foundations of public law and administrative law has also transformed the relationship between administrative authorities and counterparties from the traditional &amp;ldquo;command-obedience&amp;rdquo; model to a gradually emerging state of equality with dual legal status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreements: The Identification and Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract Since the enactment of the new Administrative Litigation Law in 2015, judges in the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s administrative division have tended to expand the boundaries of administrative agreements by emphasizing the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative duties,&amp;rdquo; while judges in the civil division of the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court have tended to restrict the boundaries based on the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative powers.&amp;rdquo; The source of this divergence lies in the inherent tension between the values of &amp;ldquo;safeguarding the public interest&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;respecting private rights&amp;rdquo; in China&amp;rsquo;s Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
