<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administrative Litigation on Chen Tianhao</title>
    <link>https://sypthu.github.io/tags/administrative-litigation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Administrative Litigation on Chen Tianhao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sypthu.github.io/tags/administrative-litigation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Litigation in China: Assessing the Chief Officials Appearance System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-litigation-in-chinaassessing-the-chief-officials-appearance-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-litigation-in-chinaassessing-the-chief-officials-appearance-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen, Wei Xu and Xiaohong Yu*
Abstract The Chief Officials Appearance System (COAS), introduced in 2015, requires government leaders to appear in court and explain their actions. Unlike other post-2014 legal reforms aiming to reduce political influence in administrative litigation, COAS uniquely actively involves political officials. This approach is based on the belief that increased participation will help officials better understand public concerns and improve administrative litigation quality. However, few studies have examined the system’s effectiveness, and existing research relies on anecdotal evidence with limited analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreement Litigation: The Construction and Improvement of the System</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreement-litigationthe-construction-and-improvement-of-the-system/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract The new &amp;ldquo;Administrative Litigation Law&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Judicial Interpretation on Administrative Agreements&amp;rdquo; have expanded the jurisdiction of administrative litigation to encompass disputes over the effectiveness of administrative agreements, performance disputes, and disputes involving high authorities. They have also &amp;ldquo;relationship-orientedly&amp;rdquo; transformed the administrative agreement litigation system. When the People&amp;rsquo;s Court handles these disputes, it should move beyond the traditional logic of reviewing the legitimacy of administrative actions and allocate the rights and interests of all parties appropriately based on the overall legal relationship of administrative agreements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Administrative Agreements: The Identification and Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 23:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sypthu.github.io/publications/administrative-agreementsthe-identification-and-boundaries/</guid>
      <description>Tianhao Chen
Abstract Since the enactment of the new Administrative Litigation Law in 2015, judges in the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court&amp;rsquo;s administrative division have tended to expand the boundaries of administrative agreements by emphasizing the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative duties,&amp;rdquo; while judges in the civil division of the Supreme People&amp;rsquo;s Court have tended to restrict the boundaries based on the element of &amp;ldquo;administrative powers.&amp;rdquo; The source of this divergence lies in the inherent tension between the values of &amp;ldquo;safeguarding the public interest&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;respecting private rights&amp;rdquo; in China&amp;rsquo;s Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
